I was one of those kids that, every time I got in the car,
كنت من هؤلاء الأطفال الذين كلما صعدوا إلى السيارة،
I basically had to roll down the window.
يفتحون النافذة.
It was usually too hot, too stuffy or just too smelly,
غالبا ما كانت السيارة مرتفعة الحرارة، أو ممتلئة جدا بالأشياء ، أو بها رائحة ما
and my father would not let us use the air conditioner.
ولم يكن أبي ليسمح لنا بتشغيل مكيف الهواء.
He said that it would overheat the engine.
كان يقول لنا أن تشغيله سيؤدي إلى ارتفاع حرارة المحرك.
And you might remember, some of you,
ومنا من قد يتذكر،
how the cars were back then, and it was
كيف كانت السيارات حينها، وأن
a common problem of overheating.
ارتفاع حرارة المحرك كانت مشكلة يعاني منها الجميع.
But it was also the signal that capped the use,
لكنها كانت دليلا على محدوية استخدام ،
or overuse, of energy-consuming devices.
أو الافراط في استخدام الأجهزة المستهلكة للطاقة.
Things have changed now. We have cars that we take across country.
لكن الأمور تغيرت، الآن لدينا سيارات يمكن أن نسافر بها بين البلدان.
We blast the air conditioning the entire way,
ننعم فيها طوال الطريق بمكيف الهواء،
and we never experience overheating.
دون أن نواجه اي ارتفاع في حرارة المحرك.
So there's no more signal for us to tell us to stop.
و لا يوجد أي مؤشر يخبرنا بأنه يجب علينا التوقف.
Great, right? Well, we have similar problems in buildings.
عظيم ، أليس كذلك ؟ حسنا ، لدينا مشاكل مشابهة في البنايات.
In the past, before air conditioning, we had thick walls.
في الماضي، قبل مكيفات الهواء ، كانت لدينا جدران سميكة .
The thick walls are great for insulation. It keeps the interior
الجدران السميكة جيدة جدا للعزل الحراري. فهي تبقي الداخل
very cool during the summertime, and warm during the wintertime,
باردا في الصيف، و دافئا في الشتاء،
and the small windows were also very good because
و النوافذ الصغيرة كانت أيضا جيدة جدا لأنها
it limited the amount of temperature transfer
تحصر كمية التبادل الحراري
between the interior and exterior.
بين الداخل و الخارج.
Then in about the 1930s, with the advent of plate glass,
بعدها ، وفي حوالي الثلاثينات من القرن الماضي ، ومع اختراع الزجاج السميك،
rolled steel and mass production, we were able
والحديد الصلب ومع الإنتاج المتزايد؛ تمكنا
to make floor-to-ceiling windows and unobstructed views,
من صنع النوافذ الممتدة من الأرضية إلى السقف، والتي لا تعيق الرؤية
and with that came the irreversible reliance on
وبالتزامن مع هذا، ظهر اعتماد لا رجعة فيه
mechanical air conditioning to cool our solar-heated spaces.
على التكييف الهوائي الميكانيكي لتبريد فضاءاتنا التي أدت الشمس إلى تسخينها
Over time, the buildings got taller and bigger,
مع مرور الوقت، أصبحت البنايات أكثر طولا وأكبر حجما،
our engineering even better, so that the mechanical systems
وهندستنا أفضل بكثير، وكذلك أنظمتنا الميكانيكية
were massive. They require a huge amount of energy.
أصبحت هائلة.وتحتاج إلى كم هائل من الطاقة.
They give off a lot of heat into the atmosphere,
وتطلق الكثير من الحرارة في الجو،
and for some of you may understand the heat island effect
ومنكم من يفهم تأثير الجزيرة الحرارية
in cities, where the urban areas are much more warm
في المدن ، حيث المناطق الحضرية أصبحت دافئة أكثر فأكثر
than the adjacent rural areas,
بالمقارنة مع المناطق القروية المجاورة،
but we also have problems that, when we lose power,
لكن لدينا بعض المشاكل من قبيل ، انه وحين انقطاع التيارالكهربائي،
we can't open a window here, and so
فاننا لا نستطيع فتح نافذة هنا ، وبالتالي
the buildings are uninhabitable and have to be made vacant
تصبح هذه البنايات غير قابلة للسكن ، ويجب إخلائها
until that air conditioning system can start up again.
حتى يعمل نظام التكييف من جديد.
Even worse, with our intention of trying to make buildings
وماهو أسوأ من ذلك، هي نوايانا في محاولة جعل البنايات
move towards a net-zero energy state, we can't do it
تتحول نحو مستوى طاقة منعدم، لا يمكننا القيام بذلك
just by making mechanical systems more and more efficient.
بجعل الأنظمة الميكانيكية أكثر فعالية فقط.
We need to look for something else, and we've gotten ourselves a little bit into a rut.
علينا أن نبحث شيء آخر، فنحن لقد وضعنا أنفسنا في مأزق نوعا ما .
So what do we do here? How do we pull ourselves and dig us
ماذا نفعل هنا ؟ كيف نسحب أنفسنا و نخرج أنفسنا
out of this hole that we've dug?
من هذه الحفرة التي حفرناها؟
If we look at biology, and many of you probably don't know,
إذا نظرنا إلى علم الأحياء، و العديد منكم ربما لا يعلمون،
I was a biology major before I went into architecture,
أنني حاصلة على الإجازة في علم الأحياء ، قبل أن أتوجه إلى المعمار،
the human skin is the organ that naturally regulates
فإن الجلد البشري ما هو الا عبارة عن عضو ينظم وبشكل طبيعي
the temperature in the body, and it's a fantastic thing.
درجة الحرارة في الجسم ،و هذا أمر مدهش.
That's the first line of defense for the body.
فهو أول خط دفاع بالنسبة للجسم.
It has pores, it has sweat glands, it has all these things
لديه مسام ، لديه غدد عرقية، ولديه كل تلك الأشياء
that work together very dynamically and very efficiently,
التي تعمل معا بحيوية و فعالية كبيرتين،
and so what I propose is that our building skins
لدا فقد كان ما اقترحته أن تكون الطبقة السطحية لبناياتنا
should be more similar to human skin,
شبيهة بجلد الإنسان،
and by doing so can be much more dynamic, responsive
وبهذا تكون أكثر حيوية ، متجاوبة
and differentiated, depending on where it is.
و مختلفة حسب موقع تواجدها.
And this gets me back to my research.
وهذا يعود بي إلى موضوع بحثي.
What I proposed first doing is looking at a different material palette to do that.
ما اقترحت فعله في البداية هو النظر إلى مجموعة من المواد لفعل هذا الأمر.
I presently, or currently, work with smart materials,
حاليا أقوم بالعمل بمواد ذكية
and a smart thermo-bimetal.
وآلة حرارية ذكية ثنائية المعدن.
First of all, I guess we call it smart because it requires
أولا،أعتقد أننا نسميها بمواد ذكية لأنها لا تتطلب
no controls and it requires no energy,
مراقبة ولا تتطلب أية طاقة
and that's a very big deal for architecture.
وهذا أمر جلل بالنسبة للهندسة.
What it is, it's a lamination of two different metals together.
إذ يتعلق الأمر بتصفيح معدنين مختلفين معا.
You can see that here by the different reflection on this side.
يمكنكم رؤية ذلك من خلال الانعكاس المختلف على هذه الجهة.
And because it has two different coefficients of expansion,
ولأن لديها معاملي توسع مختلفين،
when heated, one side will expand faster than the other
فعند تسخينها، فإن احد اطرافها يسخن بشكل أسرع من الآخر
and result in a curling action.
مما ينتج عملية شبيهة بالتجعد.
So in early prototypes I built these surfaces to try to see
لذا فقد أعددت في النماذج الأولية الاولى هذه المسطحات لمحاولة رؤية
how the curl would react to temperature and possibly allow
ردة فعل التجعد نحو الحرارة و تقصي إمكانية السماح
air to ventilate through the system,
بمرور الهواء من خلال النظام،
and in other prototypes did surfaces where the multiplicity
وفي نماذج أخرى وضعت أسطحا بحيث
of having these strips together can try to make
تكون محصلة وجودها معا هو محاولة لاستحداث
bigger movement happen when also heated,
حركات أكبر عند ارتفاع حرارتها أيضا
and currently have this installation at the Materials &amp; Applications gallery
وحاليا لدينا رواق للمعدات و الآليات و التطبيقات
in Silver Lake, close by, and it's there until August, if you want to see it.
في معرض سيلفر لاك ، القريب من هنا، وهو مفتوح إلى نهاية شهر أغسطس، إذا أردتم أن تلقوا نظرة.
It's called "Bloom," and the surface is made completely
وهو مسمى " Bloom" وسطحه مصمم بشكل كامل من
out of thermo-bimetal, and its intention is to make this canopy
قطعة حرارية ثنائية المعدن و الغرض منها صناعة هذه القبة
that does two things. One, it's a sun-shading device, so that
التي تقوم بشيئين اثنين. أولاهما مظلة شمسية تعمل على
when the sun hits the surface, it constricts the amount of sun passing through,
تقليص كمية الأشعة الشمسية التي تمر إلى الداخل،
and in other areas, it's a ventilating system,
ومن جهة أخرى، فهي تعمل كنظام للتهوية،
so that hot, trapped air underneath can actually
حيث أن الهواء الساخن بالداخل يستطيع
move through and out when necessary.
التحرك و الخروج إذا تطلب الأمر.
You can see here in this time-lapse video that the sun,
يمكنكم أن تروا من خلال هذه الفيديو أنه
as it moves across the surface, as well as the shade,
وبينما تتحرك الشمس عبرالسطح و كذلك الأمر بالنسبة للظل،
each of the tiles moves individually.
فإن كل قطعة من قطع البلاط تتحرك بمفردها.
Keep in mind, with the digital technology that we have today,
عليكم أن تتذكروا دائما، أنه بفضل التكنولوجيا الرقمية التي لدينا الآن،
this thing was made out of about 14,000 pieces
فقد تم صناعة هذا الشيء باستعمال 14،000 قطعة،
and there's no two pieces alike at all. Every single one is different.
حيث لا توجد قطعتان تشبهان بعضهما إطلاقا.كل قطعة منها فريدة من نوعها.
And the great thing with that is the fact that we can calibrate
و الأمر المذهل هنا هو إمكانية تقويم
each one to be very, very specific to its location,
كل منها بطريقة تجعلها متناسبة بشكل خاص بالنسبة لمكانها،
to the angle of the sun, and also how the thing actually curls.
مقارنة بزاوية اشعة الشمس الساقطة عليها، والكيفية التي تتجعد بها.
So this kind of proof of concept project
إذا فهذا النوع من المشاريع التي تثبت صحة الفكرة
has a lot of implications
له عدة تداعيات
to actual future application in architecture,
على مستقبل التطبيقات الهندسية،
and in this case, here you see a house,
وفي هذه الحالة ، يمكنم أن تروا هذا المنزل،
that's for a developer in China,
لمُصممٍ في الصين،
and it's actually a four-story glass box.
وهو في الواقع صندوق زجاجي من أربعة طوابق.
It's still with that glass box because we still want that visual access,
وهو لا يزال على شكل صندوق زجاجي لأننا نريد ذلك المنفذ البصري
but now it's sheathed with this thermo-bimetal layer,
لكنه الآن مغلف بهذه الطبقة الحرارية ثنائية المعدن
it's a screen that goes around it, and that layer can actually
تلتف كطبقة حماية حوله ،وتستطيع هذه الطبقة
open and close as that sun moves around on that surface.
أن تفتح أو تغلق بحسب حركة الشمس على السطح.
In addition to that, it can also screen areas for privacy,
وبالإضافة إلى ذلك، فإنه يمكن أيضا لن تخصص بعض المناطق للخصوصية،
so that it can differentiate from some of the public areas
بحيث يمكن أن تميزها عن بعض الأماكن العامة
in the space during different times of day.
خلال أوقات مختلفة من اليوم.
And what it basically implies is that, in houses now,
وما يعنيه هذا يالمقام الأول هو أننا، في البيوت الآن،
we don't need drapes or shutters or blinds anymore
لم نعد بحاجة إلى الستائر أو الستائر المعدنية أو الأغطية بعد الآن
because we can sheath the building with these things,
لأنه أصبح بإمكاننا أن نغلف المبنى بهذه الأشياء،
as well as control the amount of air conditioning you need inside that building.
وكذلك التحكم في كمية التكييف التي نحتاجها داخل هذا المبنى.
I'm also looking at trying to develop some building components for the market,
أنا أسعى أيضا في محاولة لتطوير بعض هذه المكونات ليتم تداولها في الأسواق،
and so here you see a pretty typical
فهنا نشاهد نموذجاً اعتيادياً
double-glazed window panel, and in that panel,
للوحة نافذة ذات زجاج مزدوج، وفي هذا الفراغ،
between those two pieces of glass, that double-glazing,
بين تلك القطعتين من الزجاج المزدوج،
I'm trying to work on making
أحاول العمل على انشاء
a thermo-bimetal pattern system
نظام حراري ثنائي المعدن
so that when the sun hits that outside layer
بحيث عندما تضرب الشمس الطبقة الخارجية منه
and heats that interior cavity, that thermo-bimetal
وترفع درجة حرارة هذه التجاويف الداخلية، فإن هذا النظام ثنائي المعدن
will begin to curl, and what actually will happen then
سوف يبدأ بالتجعد ، وما سيحدث بعد ذلك في الواقع
is it'll start to block out the sun
هو انه سوف يبدأ في حجب أشعة الشمس
in certain areas of the building,
في مناطق معينة من المبنى،
and totally, if necessary.
أو حتى عن المبنى كاملا عند الضرورة.
And so you can imagine, even in this application, that
وهكذا يمكنك أن تتخيل، وحتى في هذا التطبيق، أنه
in a high-rise building where the panel systems go
وفي بناية شاهقة حيث نظم للوحات يصعد
from floor to floor up to 30, 40 floors, the entire surface
من طابق إلى أخر حتى يصل إلى 30 و 40 طابقا، فإن كامل السطح
could be differentiated at different times of day
يمكنه أن يختلف في اوقات مختلفة من اليوم
depending on how that sun moves across and hits that surface.
اعتمادا على الطريقة التي تعبر بها اشعة الشمس وتضرب بها هذا السطح.
And these are some later studies that I'm working on
وهذه هي بعض الدراسات التي أعمل عليها
right now that are on the boards, where you can see,
حاليا، والتي تتمحور حول الالواح، حيث يمكنكم ان تروا
in the bottom right-hand corner, with the red, it's actually
في الركن الأيمن السفلي، مع الأحمر، انها فعلا
smaller pieces of thermometal, and it's actually going to,
عبارة عن قطع صغيرة من معدن حراري.
we're trying to make it move like cilia or eyelashes.
نحن نحاول أن نجعلها تتحرك مثل الأهداب أو الرموش.
This last project is also of components.
هذا المشروع الأخير هو أيضا من المكونات.
The influence -- and if you have noticed, one of my
التأثير - وإذ لاحظتم، فإن واحدة من
spheres of influence is biology -- is from a grasshopper.
هالات التأثير الخاصة بي هي علم الأحياء - وهي مستوحاة من الجندب.
And grasshoppers have a different kind of breathing system.
فالجنادب لها الجهاز تنفسي من نوع مختلف.
They breathe through holes in their sides called spiracles,
انها تتنفس من خلال فتحات في الجانبين تدعى خياشيم
and they bring the air through and it moves through their system to cool them down,
حيث أنها تدخل الهواء من خلالها وتحركه داخل نظامها وذلك لتبرد جسمها
and so in this project, I'm trying to look at how we can
وهكذا في هذا المشروع، فأنا أحاول أن أنظر في الكيفية التي تمكننا
consider that in architecture too, how we can bring
من محاكاة هذه العملية ايضا، كيف يمككنا ان نجعل
air through holes in the sides of a building.
الهواء يمر من خلال ثقوب موجودة في جوانب البنايات.
And so you see here some early studies of blocks,
وهكذا ترى هنا بعض الدراسات المبكرة للكتل،
where those holes are actually coming through,
والتي تأتي تلك الثقوب من خلالها في الواقع،
and this is before the thermo-bimetal is applied,
وهذا قبل تطبيق المعدن الحراري ثنائي الطبقة،
and this is after the bimetal is applied. Sorry, it's a little
وهذا بعد تطبيق المعدن الحراري ثنائي الطبقة، متأسفة، انه من الصعب
hard to see, but on the surfaces, you can see these red arrows.
قليلا أن نرى، ولكن على السطوح، يمكنك ان ترى هذه السهام الحمراء.
On the left, it's when it's cold and the thermo-bimetal
إلى اليسار، عندما يكون المعدن الحراري باردا
is flat so it will constrict air from passing through the blocks,
فنراه مسطحا بطريقة تحد من مرور الهواء بين الكتل
and on the right, the thermo-bimetal curls
وإلى اليمين، نرى المعدن وهو يتجعد
and allows that air to pass through, so those are two different
ويسمح بمرور الهواء، لذا فهذين
components that I'm working on, and again,
جزئين مختلفين أقوم بالعمل عليهما، ومجددا،
it's a completely different thing, because you can imagine
فهذا شيء مختلف تماما، لأنه يمكنك تخيل
that air could potentially be coming through the walls
كيف أن الهواء سوف يأتي من خلال الجدران
instead of opening windows.
بدلا من النوافذ المفتوحة.
So I want to leave you with one last impression about
لذلك أريد أن أترككم مع انطباع أخير عن
the project, or this kind of work and using smart materials.
المشروع، أو هذا النوع من العمل واستخدام المواد الذكية.
When you're tired of opening and closing those blinds
عندما كنت تتعب من فتح وإغلاق تلك الستائر
day after day, when you're on vacation
يوما بعد أخر، عندما تكون في إجازة
and there's no one there on the weekends to be turning off and on the controls,
عطلة نهاية الأسبوع وليس هناك أحد هناك يعمل على إيقاف وتشغيل الضوابط
or when there's a power outage, and you have
أو عندما يكون هناك انقطاع في الطاقة، ولا تمتلك
no electricity to rely on, these thermo-bimetals
اية كهرباء تعتمد عليها، فإن هذه المعادن الحرارية ثنائة الطبقة
will still be working tirelessly, efficiently
سوف تستمر في العمل دون كلل أو ملل وبكفاءة.
and endlessly. Thank you. (Applause)
شكرا (تصفيق)
(Applause)
(تصفيق)